Tajudeen Ade Muktar

Full Stack Web Developer

Full-stack web developer with over 7+ years of experience analysing, designing, developing, and integrating front-end & back-end-based applications, possesses knowledge of web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, ReactJs, Ajax, and PHP. Key achievement: created a web application that allowed 100K users to search for nearby restaurants based on their location with 95% accuracy.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer

August 2018 - 2020

Creative Digita Technology, Lagos, Nigeria

- Tutored Student Front-End and Back-End Web Development
- Worked with a team of 5 developers that created an e-commerce website using PHP, MySQL, and JavaScript within 3 months.
- Best code practice and maintenance for work done by Student/Team
- Participated in code reviews of 50 developers' ensuring that all code complied 100% with coding standards & best practices.

Front End Developer

August 2023 -Till Date

Forloop Technology Company, Lagos, Nigeria.

- Overseeing every activity going on in the company as the CEO.
- Developed front-end code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery to create a responsive web application that works across 29 devices, including desktops, tablets and mobiles.
- Optimized 60 web pages for speed and performance by eliminating unnecessary scripts/styles and increasing load time by 80%.
- Created an interactive map for a real estate company's website that allowed 7K+ users to search by neighbourhood and get real-time feedback about a property.
- Partnered with 5 UI/UX designers on redesigning Growths existing site; improving conversion rate by 80%.

Software Developer

August 2020 - August 2022

LarryShilex Global, Lagos, NG.

- Proficient in Responsive Web Design: Demonstrated expertise in crafting
 responsive and mobile-friendly web applications utilizing HTML, CSS, and
 JavaScript. Skilled in designing intuitive user interfaces that seamlessly adapt to
 diverse screen sizes and devices, ensuring an exceptional user experience across
 all platforms.
- Advanced ReactJS Proficiency: Extensive experience and mastery in ReactJS, a
 powerful JavaScript library renowned for building dynamic and interactive user
 interfaces. Proficient in leveraging Redact's component-based architecture, state
 management techniques (such as Redux or Context API), and modern development
 paradigms (including hooks and functional components) to create robust, scalable
 front-end solutions.
- Collaborative Team Contributor: Proven track record of thriving in collaborative software development environments. Adept at working closely with cross-functional teams, including designers, product managers, and fellow developers, to deliver cutting-edge software solutions. Strong communication skills, problem-solving abilities, and a collaborative mindset enable effective participation in discussions, code reviews, and team-oriented projects, ultimately driving the success of the team and the project.

CONTACT

- Lagos, Nigeria (Open to Remote)
- +2349060292183
- mk.messilless@gmail.com
- · linkedin.com/in/forloop
- github.com/officialforloop

SKILLS

Technical Skills:

- . HTML
- . CSS3
- . JavaScript
- Bootstrap (Advanced)
- WordPress (Experienced)
- Web Design
- Web Development
- ReactJs

Industry Knowledge:

- Amazon Web Services
- Front-end Development
- Back-end Development
- Web Applications

Tools and Software:

- JavaScripts
- · jQuery
- · Linux
- Apache
- Nginx

EDUCATION

Ojo High School Senior Secondary Certificate (SSCE) – 2012-2017

OTHER

- Certified Front-End Developer
- Certified Back-End
 Developer
- Certified in JavaScript
 Developer
 - Certified Web Developer
- Certified Web Designer
- Certified TypeScript
 Developer